so now that we know that each
application sees a lot of memory and
there is much less physical memory than
all the applications actually can access
the question is where is the missing
memory so let's say we have one
application with four pages another
application with let's say four pages a
physical memory with let's say for
physical frames let's say that each of
these applications is actually using all
of its pages because there are only four
in this application there is a four
entry page table that for every page
tells us which frame contains it and it
could be any frame in memory this
application also has some of its pages
in physical memory but obviously there
is not enough physical memory for all of
these pages so the question is where are
the rest of them and the answer is they
are on the hard disk so some of these
pages are not actually in memory they
are actually stored on the hard drive in
the system these pages cannot be
directly accessed by the processor
because the processor can only really
access through loads and stores the
physical memory so if the processor ever
tries to access one of these they need
to be brought from the disk before they
can be accessed we will shortly see how
that works but for now just remember
that because the virtual memory of all
the applications can significantly
exceed the size of the physical memory
some of the memory that the applications
think they have is on the disk not
really in memory at all